The State Bank of India has warned its 40 crore
customers that
their banking services may be stopped after March 31, 2022.
Airtel Payments Bank has
partnered with ICICI Lombard and is
providing
cyber insurance to its customers and
may bring its digital rupee to India in early 2023.
Friends, today in CS UK, I am going to tell you all
about three very important news,
so I hope you will
watch this video from beginning to end. Hello friends, I now welcome
you all to our channel Chalo Seekho. Let's
know friends, let's come to the first news.
State Bank of India has
warned its 40 crore customers
that if they do
not link their PAN with Aadhar card by March 31, 2022, then
their banking services will be
stopped, that is, they will be disconnected. The
earlier deadline was September 30,
2021, but due to the internet, it has been
extended to March 31, 2022.  If
you do not link your PAN card
with your Aadhaar card,
then your PAN card will be considered inactive
and some banking services will be closed for you,
along with that, you will
not be able to express those transactions. So, if you have not
yet linked your PAN card with your Aadhaar card, then
you should
go to www.incometaxindia.gov.in, there you will find 'Link
Aadhaar', tick it, then enter your PAN
number there,
after that there will be an option to 'Link Aadhaar' below,
in 30 seconds your Aadhaar and
PAN number will be linked. Now
coming to the second news, Airtel Payments Bank is
providing insurance to its customers on-site in partnership with ICICI Lombard. You must have heard about car insurance,
bike insurance,
life insurance,
but
this is cyber insurance. Now you
know that the whole world has
moved towards digital payments and with this, cyber fraud has
increased a lot, which means that
someone may take a loan in your name, identity
theft may occur, or else  Additionally, if I were to
tell you that someone makes a wrong
transaction in your name or misuses your credit card, all of these fall
under cyber fraud. To
avoid these, Airtel Payments Bank, under the influence of
ICICI Lombard, is going to
provide you with cyber insurance.
How can you get life insurance?
Their application is the Airtel Thanks
application. You can go there and make an insurance
claim. You can renounce any
insurance amount or policy you have
chosen. You can make
multiple insurance claims.
You get a zero waiting period.
You get a 90-day discovery period.
Suppose
you don't know if something has been produced in your name,
you get 90 days' time. You
can find out within the notice and make a claim.
Now, coming to the last news,
India may introduce digital currency as early as next year, i.e., 2023.
Digital Rupee is
basically a digital currency. Digital
currency does not mean that it is just
crypto.  It is not a currency, it is like crypto currency. The
technology used here is
blockchain technology. The same
technology will be used in the digital copy, but
this is not a crypto currency.
Nowadays, the electronic wallets that we are using,
which are run by private companies, are
basically
not backed by the government. There is no government
involvement here. But
this digital form, here, will be completely
issued by the Arab world, so the government
keeps an eye on it. Now, at this time,
whenever I use any electronic wallet,
your interest is
linked with private companies.
When you invest with the help of electronic wallet, the
money
first goes to that private company,
after that the money goes
to any merchant, but once this digital form comes out, then the
investment of private companies will not happen. This money which
goes to YouTube will remain hidden there, that is, the
government is keeping an eye on it,
and after that it will be transferred to the machine.
Now, see here, whatever you invest,
it will become completely transparent, that is,  The
government will always
keep an eye on it, so in a way, let's see from a good point of view whether
it comes completely in the beginning of 2030
or not. What do you think, do
you think digital Rupee will
come in the beginning of 2028 or there might be a slight delay.
Whatever your thoughts are, please do
tell me in the comment section below. So, for now, that's all for
today's CS Bulletin. I hope
you got some information from this video.
If you liked
this video, please like it and
share it with your friends. If you
like watching videos related to finals or morning, then you
must subscribe to our channel. Because I keep
bringing such interesting videos to you all. If you want an interesting topic,
please tell me in the comment section below.
I will definitely make a video on it.
See you in the next video
with another interesting topic. Thank you
very much for watching the video for sewing.